Guide to the Dudley Landon Vaill Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Dudley Landon Vaill papers
1897-1959
MS 1579
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
The papers consist primarily of correspondence received by Dudley Vaill from Clarence Day, former roommate and fellow graduate of the Yale Class of 1896. Day, author of the hit Broadway play, "Life with Father," was a prolific correspondent who enlivened his letters with ink sketches. The correspondence deals with personal matters as well as alumni activities. Memorabilia and photographs of Vaill's college days complete the collection.
Vaill, Dudley Landon
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Secretary's Office, Yale University, 1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Dudley Vaill Papers consist primarily of correspondence received by Vaill from Clarence Day, former roommate and fellow graduate of the Yale Class of 1896. Day, author of the hit Broadway play, "Life with Father," was a prolific correspondent who enlived his letters with ink sketches. Day's correspondence with Vaill, class secretary from 1916 to 1967, dealt with personal matters as well as the alumni activities of former classmates. Memorabilia and photographs of Vaill's college days complete the collection.
Biographical / Historical
Dudley Landon Vaill was born on August 30, 1873, in Winsted, Connecticut. He graduated from Phillips Academy, Andover, in 1892 and from Yale in 1896. Vaill served as class secretary from 1916 until his death. Upon graduation Vaill joined the firm of George Dudley and Son, a leather manufacturer in Winsted, and became treasurer of the company in 1898. He was president of the Winsted Savings Bank from 1914 to 1953. Vaill died on October 8, 1967.
Day, Clarence, 1874-1935; Vaill, Dudley Landon; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1896; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Correspondence to Dudley Vaill
  - Day, Clarence, 1897-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 13)
  - Day, Clarence, 1917-1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 14 - 17)
  - Day, George Parmly, 1900-1943 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Day family members, 1901, [1910?], 1936, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General, 1921-1936 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Johnston, Henry Selden: correspondence from Clarence Day, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- General correspondence: from Clarence Day to others, 1924, 1926, 1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Clippings about Clarence Day, 1922, 1935-1939, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Memorabilia/miscellany, 1907-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Photographs: college days, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 25)